looking for a comparison review over two
awesome barbells well you came to the
right place my friend and you might see
some sweat running down my face as this
video goes on that's partly because I'm
in a pretty hot garage but it's also
partly because I'm a little nervous
about choosing between the Rogue Ohio
bar and the force USA Gunner barbell but
with that being said I'm pretty excited
I can't wait to get going so why don't
we go ahead and Dive Right on into this
now what's up everybody it's Jake you
know the deal you know where I'm at I'm
in the barbering garage gym for today's
review I've got the Rogue Ohio bar and
the force USA Gunner barbell in this
video I'm going to compare these two and
I'm gonna help you decide which one
needs to be in your home gym but before
we get going I gotta let you know as
always we have reviewed a lot of
barbells on barbin.com and if you want
to browse our best list just search bar
Bend best barbells and you can find out
for yourself elf which ones that we like
the best
okay so let's kick this off with the
similarities like I tend to do with
these barbell comparison videos I will
say up front both of these barbells are
multi-purpose bars they can handle
almost anything you throw at it in the
gym so they are going to have a good
amount of qualities that are similar
alright so let's talk about the knurling
first the knurling on both of these bars
it's on the moderate side it's going to
give you a good grip even for your power
lifts but because it's not cut as deep
as a power bar it's not going to tear up
your hands you know if you were to do
some Olympic style lifts like a hang
clean or a clean and jerk you know
whatever anything with a bar just
rotating in your hands it's not going to
tear you up which is really nice like a
lot of multi-purpose bars out there you
don't have a center knurling on either
one of these barbells I tend to like
that if you've seen my other videos
you'll know that but
I understand why some people don't like
that because there's a lot of movements
that that can come in handy with because
it's going to give you more traction
more grip on your body but I like it
because it's not going to irritate my
skin if I were to do some power lifts
the Dual neural markings on both these
barbells also pretty common because
you're able to do both power lifting and
Olympic style lifts with these barbells
so these are going to give you identical
hand placement as you go to get set up
for your wide grip lifts so that's a
really nice touch both of the sleeves
spin that's going to be really nice as
well for those Olympic style lifts it's
going to reduce the amount of torque
that your wrists and your elbows have to
go under during those lifts so it's
going to help you out you know prevent
some injury from happening and you also
have grooves in both of the loading
sleeves here and that's just going to be
really nice especially when you do any
type of lift where the bar tends to drop
or slam into the ground you're gonna
have a higher chance of keeping your
plates in their original placement
[Music]
okay so when it comes to the differences
between these two barbells there's a
handful that kind of stood out to me in
my opinion all right so let's talk about
tinsel strength first but before I do
that it is worth mentioning that the
Rogue Ohio bar does come in a couple
different coding options and the tensile
strength rating is going to change so we
have the stainless steel version that's
what we're basing this comparison off of
this has a rating of 200 000 PSI while
the other coding options available with
this barbell have a rating of 190 000
PSI now that's a really solid rating but
with the force USA Gunner there's a
rating of 235
000 PSI which is the strongest bar that
I've ever used now I did say there's
other coding options available with the
Ohio but that's not the case with the
Gunner alright so this comes in a black
zinc finish the only thing you're
getting in terms of the finish here
except for with the sleeves the sleeves
you do have the option of regular zinc
like I have on here right now there's
also black zinc you can add on there
with this stainless steel version of the
Ohio these are Chrome sleeves but you
can also opt in for stainless steel
sleeves if you want a fully stainless
steel build
okay so with that being said the pricing
is a little bit different too so with
the Ohio this version is listed right
around 370 bucks but like I said if you
wanted those stainless steel sleeves you
can get them but it's going to cost you
another 100 bucks or so once you add on
shipping that could cost you around 500
dollars
now in terms of the other options with
the Ohio you do have a black zinc option
as well as an e-coat those are going to
be right around 300 305 dollars the
black oxide version is about 320 and the
custom option that is there for you you
can you know get the finish of your
choice and you can do a whole lot of
stuff with it it's gonna be about 350
bucks with the Gunner so this version I
have right here with the regular zinc
sleeves it's listed at 250 and once you
add on shipping that's going to be right
around 300 while if you were to get the
black zinc sleeves that's going to end
up being 350 dollars once you add on
shipping because those sleeves are 50
more than these right here and I don't
really think you're going to find much
of a difference in fighting off rust and
corrosion so if you want to say 50 bucks
I mean you could definitely just go with
the regular zinc that we have right here
continuing with some differences now the
knurling it's it's a little different as
well
um they're both really solid don't get
me wrong they're always really solid I
do like the knurling on the Gunner but
it does seem a little bit more slippery
than the knurling right here with the
Ohio bar I think that's just because
this has a coating on it and you know
this is stainless steel so it doesn't
also mentioned earlier that the sleeves
act the same you know they both spin
it's gonna be really nice for those
Olympic style lifts like I said they
look and act similar but they're pretty
different the Ohio bar utilizes bronze
bushings to get you that nice spin for
your lifts and that's pretty common with
you know multi-purpose bars such as this
bronze bushings tend to degrade at a
pretty slow rate so with Force USA they
actually used steel stainless steel
bushings they also paired five needle
bearings in the sleeves so I think you
get a smoother Spin and it's a little
bit quicker as well and I think the
stainless steel is really just gonna you
know fight off corrosion better than
bronze will in the sleeves continuing
with the sleeves here yeah they both
have grooves in them it's going to help
you in terms of keeping your plates
locked into place but once you really
put your hands on both of them
I mean the Gunner it just gets it done
for me they're cut significantly deeper
than the Ohio bar so I think you're
actually gonna have an even more
increased chance of keeping those plates
in their original placement but that
doesn't mean you can't use a weight
collar I would still use one because the
last thing you want is for one to
eventually slide down and fall off or
whatever like just for your own safety
please use one just going back to the
finish on both of these barbells now
this is stainless steel this is going to
be ideal in terms of fighting off rust
and corrosion especially if you're like
me and you're in a pretty hot garage you
know you have a higher chance of you
know corrosion forming on your equipment
you know with this black zinc it's
definitely going to help it's better
than some other coating options out
there but you know if you're really
comparing this it's not really close in
my opinion so you're going to want to
clean this barbell and just just to make
sure that it's in in you know that
pristine condition which is something
that you really won't have to worry
about as much I still think you should
do it but you don't have to worry about
it as much with this stainless steel
Ohio bar
okay so let's talk about the money now
and what you can expect to spend on both
of these barbells now once again this is
the stainless steel version of the Ohio
bar and we do in fact have the Chrome
sleeves on this bar so this one's going
to be right around 400 maybe a little
bit more you know once you tack on your
shipping and then you know once again if
you do want the stainless steel sleeves
which looks pretty good it's going to
really be the optimal choice of fighting
off corrosion it's going to cost you
around 500 maybe with some change now on
the other hand with the force USA Gunner
you're not going to spend over 350
dollars regardless of if you wanted the
regular zinc finish on your sleeves like
we have or the black zinc finish it's
really nice because you are going to
save some money does have a higher
tensile strength rating and I forgot to
mention this a minute ago it also is
rated to hold more weight so the Ohio
bar can hold up to 1260 pounds while the
Gunner can hold up to 1500 pounds so my
power lifters out there this is a pretty
good option for you to consider if you
haven't caught on by now now either way
you know
these are not cheap right I mean this is
about 500 or so for this version of the
Ohio bar and believe it or not there's
actually a couple that are more
expensive than this one right but in
terms of you know weight rating and
tensile strength rating
I don't know if you can find a better
deal than what you're going to find with
the Gunner right here I mean
235 000 PSI that's ridiculous sorry
that's just that's ridiculous so either
way though if you don't want to spend
that much money up front on either one
of these barbells I really don't blame
you fortunately both companies are going
to allow you to finance your purchase so
starting with the Ohio bar Rogue is
going to allow you to use pay later from
PayPal as well as a firm
regardless of which one you decide to go
with
you're going to have payments of around
130 bucks a month I will say though with
a firm they are going to run a credit
score check on you and that might impact
your payments a little bit and you know
make you pay just a little bit more with
the force USA Gunner you can only use a
firm and same thing with in terms of
credit score with the firm that could
affect these pricings I'm about to
mention so with the regular zinc finish
on the sleeves you're looking at
starting around 21 a month while if you
had the black zinc on your sleeves it's
gonna be about 25 a month okay so if
money is your main deciding factor
that's what's really driving your
decision on what you want to decide
between these two barbells
you might want to go with the Gunner
because yeah you're saving some money
but you're not compromising tinsel
strength rating or overall weight rating
because both of those ratings are higher
than the Ohio bar you know you can
really do a lot with this barbell it's
just as versatile as the Ohio bar but
you know you can load more weight onto
it all you know while saving at least
150 bucks which is pretty nice now I
will say though the materials used could
definitely have a factor in that price
because somebody like myself you know
I'm in a pretty hot garage all my
equipment is
I'm gonna have to take care of you know
this black zinc finish more than I will
with this stainless steel
stainless steel if you don't know if you
haven't heard me say it in the past it's
really it's just the head honcho it's
the best way to put it head honcho in
terms of fighting off rust and corrosion
it's gonna be your best bet you know
you're not gonna have to clean it as
much but you know if you want to save
that money you can definitely clean this
a couple times a month and it should
stay in good shape and especially if
you're in a climate controlled
environment I don't think you're really
going to have to worry about that like
I'm gonna have to
foreign
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features that you're going
to find with both of these barbells but
I'm going to kick this part of the video
off with the Ohio bar okay so once again
this is the stainless steel version of
this bar arguably the highest quality
you know build you could ask for with a
barbell you do have bronze bushings in
the sleeves that are going to allow them
to spin really nice during those Olympic
style lifts because there's going to be
less torque on your wrists and your
elbows so that's really nice can
decrease the chances of injury you also
do have a Groove pattern on your sleeves
right here and that's going to be really
nice in terms of keeping your plates in
their original placement but you should
still use some weight collars just to
help that out a little bit but also for
your own safety this is rated to hold up
to 1260 pounds in the stainless steel
version does have a tensile strength
rating of 200 000 PSI if you were to go
with one of those other options those
are going to dip down in terms of
tensile strength to 190 000 PSI Ai and
the weight rating I'm not too sure about
but I would imagine that's also going to
see a dip and not be able to hold as
much weight as this stainless steel
version can now the knurling here it's
not abrasive I really like the knurling
pattern right here they went with a
volcano style pattern and if you don't
know what that is
essentially each marking here dips in as
a volcano would so you have four points
of contact per each marking on your hand
you know as opposed to a mountain style
grip pattern where you only have one
point of contact because those you know
resemble a mountain they point up
so I think this is the optimal choice in
terms of a pattern because bigger
surface area and that I think is going
to lead to a better grip the Dual neural
markings right here really nice you know
if you want to do a wide grip bench
press you can get identical hand
placement and the same goes you know for
a wide grip power clean identical hand
placement so that's really nice you
don't have to worry about you know one
hand being out wider than the other and
then everything being all out of whack
that's not fun you also don't have a
center knurling on this barbell I
personally like that but I definitely
understand why some people don't because
you definitely lose out on a little bit
of a grip you know say you wanted to do
you know a clean and jerk or you know
hang clean power clean really whatever
anything where the bar kind of needs to
rest up here at least for a second
you know you have a better chance of
that bar sticking to you with that
knurling right there but that also could
lead to irritation and kind of you know
irritate you I guess that's the best way
to put it irritate your skin and I don't
like that you know I don't want that to
happen so I'm cool without that being
there and I can also keep the bar on my
back just fine without the center
knurling like I said it's personal
preference right there only thing is you
know some people might think it's a
bummer you don't even have the option of
adding that on to this barbell and last
but certainly not least I'm going to
touch on it again stainless steel
awesome awesome awesome in terms of
fighting off rust and corrosion somebody
like myself you know this is what I need
so if you're like me you really might
want to consider adding this stainless
steel version to your home gym
okay now when it comes to the Gunner
once again this is a black zinc barbell
and you do have the option of either
regular zinc or black zinc coating on
your sleeves once again I don't think
it's going to make a difference in terms
of fighting off corrosion on the sleeves
it's just a personal preference and how
you want your barbell to look
this is a 20 kilogram version of this
barbell it's the only version actually
that it's available in same goes with
the Ohio bar so if you're looking for a
15 or 10 kilogram version of either bar
well bad news you're gonna have to keep
looking elsewhere for that this is rated
to hold up to 1500 pounds and it has
that Elite tensile strength rating of
235 000 PSI that was ranting and raving
about earlier that's just super nice
okay it's just super nice now the
knurling here is also on the moderate
side I can't tell exactly what type of
pattern they used I don't have a
magnifying glass for y'all but you know
looking up close it does seem to
resemble a volcano style pattern as well
so I think you're going to get a really
good grip right here it's a nice surface
area on your hands with each individual
marking and you know because it is
moderate it's going to be a really good
fit for the majority of your lifts and I
think for the majority of weight lifters
out there the only downside in terms of
the grip would probably just be the fact
that it is coated you know with a
stainless steel bar I feel like you can
get a better grip but that's not to take
anything away from the grip that you're
finding with this barbell
you also don't have a center knurling on
this bar you know same situation as with
the Ohio bar pros and cons with it you
know some people like it some people
don't like it just personal preference
but you don't even have the option of
adding that on there so that could be a
bummer for some people
dual neural markings here as well the
sleeves do spin and what I think is you
know one of the smoothest spins that
I've experienced and that's definitely
due to the fact that you have five
needle bearings paired up with stainless
steel bushings in your sleeves so it's
going to give you that really nice spin
one of the biggest differences in my
opinion you know other than the tensile
strength rating and the coating options
is the grooved pattern on these sleeves
they're cut really deep that was one of
the first things I noticed as I was
getting my hands on both of these
barbells is that they're just cut
significantly deeper and I think you're
definitely going to have especially if
you toss on some weight colors which you
should
a way better chance of keeping your
plates in their original placement with
this barbell really as opposed to any
other barbell and lastly with the build
on this Gunner
you know I really do enjoy the way it
looks I really do like a black zinc
barbell it just looks really good in the
gym it's just a personal aesthetic for
me that I like but me being in this
pretty you know steamy garage gym like
I'm gonna have to clean this more often
than I will with this stainless steel
bar that's not to mean don't get it just
because you need to clean it because I
think you should clean all of your stuff
regardless of the coating but I'm
definitely gonna have to clean this more
frequently than I will with the
stainless steel Ohio bar
foreign
okay so let's do a quick walk around
with both of these barbells now we're
going to start with the stainless steel
version of the Ohio bar now stainless
steel once again is the king in terms of
fighting off rust and corrosion
especially you know in a steamy garage
like I'm in right now now the knurling
is on the moderate side but it still is
going to give you a really solid grip
really regardless of what you're doing
it does have a volcano pattern which I
personally love I think it's probably
the best pattern you could ask for with
a barbell you don't have a center
knurling right here you don't even have
the option of adding one on that could
be a bummer for a lot of people but you
know with the multi-purpose bar such as
these right here that's pretty common
you also have dual neural markings right
here for your wide grips on your power
lifts and your Olympic style lifts now
if we go further down here you'll see
you do in fact have bronze bushings in
the sleeves it's going to give you a
nice controlled spin you know it's going
to be really helpful during your Olympic
lifts but they don't spin out of control
so that's going to be ideal for your
power lifts as well now you do have a
Groove pattern right here it's going to
decrease the chances of your weight
plates sliding down the sleeves as you
work out but when you compare it to the
Gunner
it's not really close so with the Gunner
the groove pattern right here is cut
significantly deeper and during my time
with both of these barbells I found more
success in keeping my plates in their
original placement while I'm working out
the sleeves also spin at a faster rate
and for a little bit longer time so it's
probably going to be better to do
Olympic style lifts with this barbell
because of that extra spin
so instead of bronze bushings they used
stainless steel bushings and paired that
up with five needle bearings in both of
the sleeves so essentially that's just
going to give you a more smooth and
controlled spin while you're lifting now
these are Chrome on the Ohio bar you do
have the option for stainless steel and
with the Gunner this is regular zinc and
you have the option for black zinc to go
along with the black zinc finish of the
actual barbell now the knurling here is
also pretty solid it gave me a pretty
good grip during all of my lifts I don't
know exactly what style of pattern they
use but it does seem to resemble a
volcano style as well I just don't have
a magnifying glass it's not listed
online so I don't know exactly
but with that being said it might not
give you as good of a grip as this
stainless steel Ohio bar can because the
stainless steel doesn't have a coating
on it and you know same scenario with
the Ohio bar you don't have the option
of a center neural and you also have
dual neural markings for your wide grips
on your power lifts as well as your
Olympic lifts
okay so now time for the fun part which
barbell should you go with
this was a really tough decision for me
it was arguably the toughest decision
I've had to make regarding a barbell
Face-Off now when you make your decision
I suggest using the same thought process
that I did so I'm gonna suggest you
think of the money the materials the
tensile strength and the grip that
you're going to get from the knurling so
starting with the money first you know
once again the Ohio bar is the more
expensive of these two bar bills and
that's likely due to the fact that it is
stainless steel but remember it does
have you know a lower weight rating as
well as a lower tensile strength rating
so if you want to save some money over a
hundred dollars as well as have a
barbell that's as strong as a Mack truck
I'd suggest going with the force USA
Gunner because you know it does have
that tensile strength rating of 235 000
PSI as opposed to 200 000 PSI with the
Ohio bar as well as the weight rating
this one's rated at 1500 pounds while
the Ohio I was rated at one thousand two
hundred sixty pounds however if you are
in a humid garage gym such as myself you
might not be too crazy about this black
zinc coating because it's not going to
offer as much protection from corrosion
as this stainless steel can plus I think
the stainless steel is going to give you
a better grip overall because it's not
coated you know that's huge for me and
I'm sure it is for the majority of y'all
if not all of y'all watching I mean who
doesn't want an optimal grip for all of
their lifts so you're going to want to
keep all these things in mind when you
go to make your next purchase especially
you know comparing between these two
barbells specifically so if you're power
cleaning you know an absurd amount of
weight the Gunner is probably going to
be the bar for you because it does have
that higher weight rating and tinsel
strength rating so it's going to handle
more that punishment than the Ohio bar
can but you know on the flip side if you
need a barbell you know specifically to
fight off rust and corrosion you know
the stainless steel build of the Ohio
bar is definitely going to be the best
choice in that regard
all right well that's a wrap on today's
comparison over the Rogue Ohio bar in
the force USA Gunner barbell y'all these
are two awesome options that I think you
should definitely consider when looking
to add a new barbell to your home gym
but now it's time for the hardest
decision of the day
which one would I go with if I
absolutely had to choose I really didn't
want to do this going into this video
the Ohio bar really it's just been my
baby lately
but I think I'm gonna have to go with
the Gunner I'm gonna save some money it
has you know a way higher tinsel
strength rating as well as a higher
overall weight rating and you know I
don't mind cleaning it from time to time
just to keep it in good shape the
knurling you know might not give me as
good of a grip as the Ohio bar can but
you know I can power through that and I
just really love how deep cut these
grooves are on these loading sleeves now
with that being said that's not to take
anything away from the Ohio bar this is
still a very solid barbell I just called
it my baby you know this is a very good
barbell if you are keeping your stuff in
a garage like me you know you're gonna
have to clean the Gunner more frequently
than you will with this stainless steel
Ohio bar now you should absolutely still
clean this barbell just to keep it in
good shape you should clean all of your
equipment just to keep everything in
good shape why would you not but if
that's something you don't want to do as
frequently you know this is going to be
that you know option for you but me
personally I really don't mind doing
that it doesn't take me very long to do
it so that's you know I'd rather save
the money and have you know some
features that the Ohio bar just doesn't
have thanks for watching everybody I
hope this video was really helpful and I
was able to provide a little bit more
insight on both of these barbells maybe
even help you decide which one of these
to add to your home gym
as always stay on the lookout for my
next review but for now you should
definitely head over to barbin.com and
you can read more about this comparison
right here just go ahead and search bar
Bend Rogue Ohio bar versus Force USA
Gunner barbell and you can read
everything that I discuss here today
with y'all now I don't know about you
I'm gonna go lift some weight I suggest
you do the exact same thing I'll see
y'all next time
foreign